Dakota Baker

- (859) 629-9847 Github: https://github.com/DakotaWBaker Email: dakotabwayne14@gmail.com
- LinkedIn: https://dakotawbaker.github.io/react-portfolio/
 Portfolio: https://dakotawbaker.github.io/react-portfolio/

Well-qualified *Full Stack Engineer* familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages, and a never-ending drive to acquire new skills and concepts. Knowledgeable of *back-end and front-end development* requirements. Handles any part of the process with ease, and Capability to quickly learn and assimilate new skills and technologies in a fast-paced atmosphere. *Collaborative team player* earned through 4 years of military service with excellent technical abilities. Looking to expand my knowledge as a software engineer, and work for a company that will have me continuously learning new skills.

KEY PROJECTS

RuneLink Dec. 2022

- Social companion site built for users to be able to keep up with all things runescape. This project is built with react.js on the front end and Django Rest framework on the backend!
- Link to source code https://github.com/DakotaWBaker/RuneLink
- Live link https://tonal-benefit-365714.web.app/

Django Jams Nov. 2022

- Created a music library database/API with Django.
- Set up a Python/Django/Django REST Framework API app, creating models that can be migrated into the database from a reference to a DB Diagram to serve as the backend for an application like Spotify or Apple Music.
- Link to source code https://github.com/DakotaWBaker/Django-Jams

SKILLS

Attention to Detail | Agile software development methodology | Oral and written communication | Teamwork and Collaboration | Self-Motivated | HTML 5 | CSS 3 | Javascript | React.JS | Python | Django | REST | Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) | Test-Driven Development (TDD) | Unit Testing | UI/UX Design | Self-Driven | Critical Thinking | Software Version Control (git) | Effective time-management | Performance under pressure | Strong problem-solving skills

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rideshare Driver Nov. 2019 - Sep. 2022

Uber LLC | Lexington, KY

- Optimized profitable time by anticipating surge areas, targeting highly trafficked sectors and daisy-chaining rides resulting in maximize customer satisfaction.
- Achieved high customer ratings on post-trip surveys for timeliness, vehicle cleanliness and customer service.
- Placed safety as top priority for rides and followed community guidelines for engaging emergency personnel resulting in 0
 accidents and 4.97 out of 5 rating

Infantry Team Leader Sep. 2015 - Nov. 2019

U.S Army | Fort Polk, LA

- Led fire team during infantry dismounted battle drills and situational training exercises.
- Directed logistical training procedures in accordance with military regulations.
- Established reports on equipment status, incidences, personnel readiness and intelligence for superiors.

- Instructed personnel in de-escalation and conflict resolution techniques for use in foreign national negotiations and cooperative actions.
- Attained Expert Marksmanship qualification badge and maximum score on physical training test resulting in getting promoted above peers.
- Learned and executed effective decision making skills in high pressure situations.

EDUCATION

Web Developer Bootcamp Awesome Inc. Sep. 2022 - Dec. 2022

The Web Developer Bootcamp is a 3-month, full-time training program for aspiring web developers. The curriculum was designed in collaboration with local technology employers to prepare individuals to dive into a career in web development. The intense training program is designed to take students from the basics of programming to competency in building modern web applications. It includes over 500 hours of hands-on training, gaining experience while building 10+ software projects in an Agile environment, using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Django, React, Google Cloud, GitHub, and more.